Guide to the Looks Like Rain: The Songwriting Legacy of Mickey Newbury research collection, 2011-2020 MS 939
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Looks Like Rain: The Songwriting Legacy of Mickey Newbury research collection
2011-2020
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Atkinson, Brian T.
MS 939
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
This collection consists of the audio research interviews and manuscript materials for the book, "Looks Like Rain: The Songwriting Legacy of Mickey Newbury" by Brian T. Atkinson.
Biographical / Historical
Beginning in earnest in 2018, Brian T. Atkinson conducted interviews with people associated with Houston singer-wongwriter Mickey Newbury. This book like Atkinson's others relies on the interviewees telling the story of the songwriter. "Looks Like Rain: The Songwriting Legacy of Mickey Newbury" was published in May of 2021.
Brian T. Atkinson's other works focus on Townes Van Zandt, Roky Erickson, Ray Wylie Hubbard, Billie Joe Shaver, among others. Most of his books are written as part of the John and Robin Dickson series in Texas Music, sponsored by the Center for Texas Music History, Texas State University.
Content Description
This collection consists of the audio research interviews, notes, correspondence, and manuscript for the book, "Looks Like Rain: The Songwriting Legacy of Mickey Newbury" by Brian T. Atkinson.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
The vast majority of this collection is open for research except cassette tapes labeled "restricted conversation" are restricted until August 14, 2077.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Brian T. Atkinson in August 2020.
Index Terms
Subjects
Folk music -- Texas -- Houston; Music
Document Types
Folk music
Subjects (Persons)
Newbury, Mickey, 1940-2002
- Series I: General files
  - Correspondence, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes and press, 2011-2018 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Original manuscript, 2020 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II: Cassette tapes
  - Claire Mullalley-Trooper / Robbyn Dopo-Ray, 2018-01-19; 2018-04-04 (Box 2)
  - Charlie McCoy / Sam Baker, 2019-03-18; 2019-03-20 (Box 2)
  - Gretchen Peters / Allen Frizzell, 2018-06-16; 2018-09-20 (Box 2)
  - Charlie Worsham / George Ensle, 2018-06-18; 2019-07-09 (Box 2)
  - Norie Guthrie, 2018-06-20 (Box 2)
  - Mickey Gilley / Jerry Decicca, 2018-06-27 (Box 2)
  - Darrell Scott, 2018-06-27 (Box 2)
  - Andrew Combs, 2018-06-28 (Box 2)
  - Ramblin' Jack Elliott / Chris Campion, 2018-06-29; 2018-09-20 (Box 2)
  - Rodney Crowell / Donnie Fritt, 2018-06-29; 2018-08-29 (Box 2)
  - Jonny Fritz / Norbert Putnam, 2018-07-02; 2018-07-03 (Box 2)
  - Bobby Bare / Buffy St. Marie, 2018-07-03; 2018-07-24 (Box 2)
  - Norbert Putnam, 2018-07-03 (Box 2)
  - Chris Gantry, 2018-07-03 (Box 2)
  - Randy Dodds, 2018-07-11 (Box 2)
  - Jennifer Warnes / Courtney T. Allen, 2018-07-12; 2018-07-18 (Box 2)
  - Matt Harlan / Johnny Lee, 2018-07-12; 2018-07-13 (Box 2)
  - Ed Bruce, 2018-07-15 (Box 2)
  - Harold Eggers (restricted conversation), 2018-07-31; 2019-07-15 (Box 2)
  - Carry Murray, 2018-08-02 (Box 2)
  - David Shepherd Grossman, 2018-08-06 (Box 2)
  - Wayne Moss, 2018-08-07 (Box 2)
  - Matraca Berg / Chuck Prophet, 2018-08-10; 2018-08-17 (Box 2)
  - Joshua Hedley / Donnie Fritts, 2018-08-21; 2018-08-28 (Box 2)
  - Leslie Satcher / Pat Alger (restricted conversation), 2018-08-30; 2018-09-08 (Box 2)
  - Dallas Frazier / Fred Koller, 2018-09-05; 2018-09-07 (Box 2)
  - Fred Koller (restricted conversation) / Pat Alger, 2018-09-07; 2018-09-08 (Box 2)
  - Chris Campion / Allen Frizzell, 2018-09-20 (Box 2)
  - Billy Swan / Richard Leigh, 2018-09-29; 2019-05-21 (Box 2)
  - Chris Smither, 2018-10-03 (Box 2)
  - Chris Newbury, 2018-10-12 (Box 2)
  - Chris Newbury / Fred Eagle Smith, 2018-10-12; 2018-10-20 (Box 2)
  - Noel McKay / Joe Henry, 2018-10-18; 2018-10-22 (Box 2)
  - Joe Henry, 2018-10-24 (Box 2)
  - Matt Harlan / Evan Blanc, 2018-11-12; 2018-12-17 (Box 2)
  - Ernie Bunch (restricted conversation), 2019-03-13 (Box 2)
  - Sam Baker / Bucky Wilkin, 2019-03-19; 2019-03-21 (Box 2)
  - Bucky Wilkin / Owsley Manier, 2019-03-21; 2019-03-22 (Box 2)
  - Owsley Manier, 2019-03-22 (Box 2)
  - Jack Williams, 2019-03-27 (Box 2)
  - Jack Williams, 2019-03-27 (Box 2)
  - Will Oldham, 2019-03-27 (Box 2)
  - Chris Newbury (restricted conversation), 2019-04-02 (Box 2)
  - Jay Bolotin, 2019-04-04 (Box 2)
  - Jay Bolotin, 2019-04-04 (Box 2)
  - Jerry Newbury, 2019-04-06 (Box 2)
  - Susan Newbury (restricted conversation), 2019-04-07 (Box 2)
  - John Carrick / Chris Newbury (restricted conversation), 2019-04-08; 2019-04-30 (Box 2)
  - Ray Wylie Hubbard / Will Kimbrough, 2019-05-08; 2019-05-13 (Box 2)
  - Will Kimbrough / Billy Edd Wheeler, 2019-05-13; 2019-05-23 (Box 2)
  - Susan Newbury, 2019-05-31 (Box 2)
  - Susan Newbury, 2019-05-31 (Box 2)
  - Bob Dipiero, 2019-06-04 (Box 2)
  - Bob Rosemurgy, 2019-06-21 (Box 2)
  - Jon Mark Stone, 2019-06-21 (Box 2)
  - Bob Rosemurgy, 2019-06-21 (Box 2)
  - John Lomax III, 2019-07-02 (Box 2)
  - John Nova Lomax, 2019-07-05 (Box 2)
  - Larry Gatlin, 2019-07-18 (Box 2)
  - Joe Gilchrist, 2019-07-18 (Box 2)
  - Robert Ellis / Joe Pug, 2019-07-19; 2019-07-29 (Box 2)
  - Juan Contreras, 2019-07-23 (Box 2)
  - Joe Gilchrist, 2019-07-28 (Box 2)
  - Harold Eggers, 2019-07-29 (Box 2)
  - Steve Earle / Chris Newbury (restricted conversation), 2019-08-10 (Box 2)